<document>
  <properties>
  </properties>
  <body>
    <section name="Plugins">
      <subsection name="Workflow">
	<p>Each plugin implements it's own set of routines/tasks to
	run to accomplish the goal of classifying variants into a
	'bin'.  Each plugin has been developed on a per study basis
	where each study has it's own set of requirements.  At a
	minimum, this means running the following tasks
	sequencially:</p>
	<ol>
	  <li>Load VCF data into the LocatedVariants table (var.loc_var).</li>
	  <li>Annotate the newly created LocatedVariants &amp; add to
	  the appropriate Variants table (refseq.variants_61_2 for
	  Genomic Reference build 37 or refseq.variants_78_4 for
	  Genomic Reference build 38)</li>
	  <li>Update frequency data.</li>
	  <li>Add newly created LocatedVariants to the appropriate
	  'bin' having added additional metadata (ie, clinvar
	  assertions, hgmd tag, etc.).</li>
	  <li>Generate Report</li>
	</ol>
	<p>The workflow is executed using the BPM engine from
	Activiti.  As such, a BPMN file is used to specify the tasks
	used.</p>
      </subsection>
      <subsection name="Executor">
	<p>The binning project registers a ThreadPoolExecutor as a
	container-based service intending to manage binning runs.  It
	has a thread pool size of one with a max size of one...meaning
	that only one binning worfklow will be run at a time.</p>
      </subsection>
      <subsection name="RESTful Service">
	<p>Each plugin has a RESTful service to expose 2
	functions:</p>
	<ul>
	  <li>Adding a binning job (submit).  This service returns the
	  binning job identifier (Long).</li>
	  <li>Checking the status of a binning job (lookupStatus).
	  This service returns a the status of the binning job
	  (String).</li>
	</ul>
      </subsection>
    </section>
    <section name="Examples">
      <p>There are a number of binning workflows on github.  The
      following is an incomplete list of binning workflows that we are
      currently using in production.</p>
      <ul>
	<li><a href="http://github.com/jdr0887/binning-workflow-diagnostic-gs">Diagnostic GeneScreen</a></li>
	<li><a href="http://github.com/jdr0887/binning-workflow-diagnostic-ncgenes">Diagnostic NCGenes</a></li>
	<li><a href="http://github.com/jdr0887/binning-workflow-diagnostic-ncnexus">Diagnostic NCNEXUS</a></li>
      </ul>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>
